John cornelius's Vanishing nickel was
first seen around the world when Doug
Henning performed it on his worldwide
television special the vanish and nickel
looks like real magic and even though it
was created so many years ago it is
still blowing Minds even today let's
talk about it roll a
[Music]
tape magic product
review Hello friends and welcome back to
the piper Magic magc product review I'm
your host Nick K and today we are
looking at Vanishing nickel by John
Cornelius imagine displaying a coin in
your open hand your fingers slowly close
around the coin and when you reopen your
hand the coin has magically vanished
with a finger spread wide apart the hand
slowly turned over showing no trace of
the coin on the back side of the hand
the coin has vanished completely lastly
the hand is again closed and when
reopened the coin has magic Ally
appeared right in the middle of your
hand what you get now I got to try and
do this without giving away the method
in the package you get some wax some
practice gimmick some invisible gimmick
a gimmick nickel and a video tutorial
explaining how to set up the gimmick and
perform the trick I think I got away
with that one difficulty this isn't
difficult to perform but it is knacky
the most difficult part of this whole
project is probably constructing the
gimmick especially if you have bad
eyesight but once you've made the
gimmick you'll be able to perform this
repeatedly so worth the effort pros and
cons Pro all the gimmicks are included
in the package there is no black art no
slight of hand it's easy to perform it's
easy to learn and the online
instructions cover everything really
well they cover the economy of movement
of getting in and out of the effect and
all just looks really really natural
cons you are going to need to practice
this is a really angly trick and it's
going to be difficult to perform because
it's engineered for you to perform it
with your hand kind of away from your
body so it's going to be very difficult
obviously perform in the surround it's
also going to be a little knacky because
the invisible gimmick is fragile if you
know what I mean so with that in mind
you might want to remove your watch or
bracelet or any type of jewelry that you
have in your arms just to ensure that
you don't break the gimmick but don't
worry too much I mean all the advice
given in the tutorial is really really
handy on how to get in and out of the
trick you the gimmick and to protect it
so they cover this in a really really
good way so thumbs up on that one cost
Piper magic have this for $48 Aussie
which equates to about
$30 is it worth it absolutely I mean
just for the materials alone that you
supplied in this package that's worth
the price alone so it is such a bargain
but like always stick around to the end
of the video so we can give you a
discount code because we're very nice
people at Piper magic seriously Shawn
Piper is a lovely guy and if you agree
give a thumbs up to the video and if you
just disagree don't give a thumbs down I
really hope no one gives a thumbs down
who is this for this is for any
performer looking to perform a really
impossible piece of magic and is willing
to put the time into making it look
awesome it's a great trick for closeup
and a perfect trick for anyone
performing on social media so if that
sounds like you I say get it and if
you're going to get it make sure you get
it from Piper magic.com auu and use
discount code Piper guys so you can get
a discount on an already awesome product
not just on this purchase but all of
your Piper magic purchases also don't
forget to scope out the magic guys
podcast where each week I alongside my
co-host Doug KH and Josh Nido get
together and we talk all things magic
and have a really fun time doing that so
scope that out links are in the
description below also don't forget to
like And subscribe to this channel so I
can keep bringing you awesome things to
review thank you guys so much for
watching and I will see you next time on
the piper mag product review
[Music]
peace